Christhian David Santander Figueroa

Colombia CO

□ (+57) 3003197499 | Schristhian0512@gmail.com | Gigithub.com/christhian0512 | Inlinkedin.com/in/chriscdsf0512/

Summary.

Bilingual engineer with a passion for learning and taking on challenges, quick learner with interest in multimedia and data analysis related projects, able to work with multidisciplinary teams, coordinate efforts, experienced in web development with and understanding of Scrum, c++, java, php, html, javascript, c#, sql, microsoft BI tools, sharepoint, Oracle DB, Laravel, git, unity, D3, etc.

Education

Universidad del Valle Cali, Colombia

B.S. in Software Engineering

Aug. 2010 - Oct. 2015

• Graduated with a meritorious thesis for the development of the app VT-Mobile

CertiProf LLC

Scrum Foundations Professional Certificate

Oct 2017

SFPC Exam

CertiProf LLC Cali, Colombia

Scrum Master Professional Certificate Mar. 2018

SMPC Exam

Courses and symposiums

Cali, Colombia

Others

- 7° symposium of research engineering faculty universidad del valle, presentation "hacia el estudio de estrategias computacionales para potenciar la Vigilancia Tecnológica, un enfoque interdisciplinario en Ingeniería de Sistemas y Computación" Nov 2014
- Third person videogame design in unity, Sena Aug 2015
- Berlitz Proficiency Test 82/100 B2 (2011)

Skills____

Programming c++, java, php, html/css, javascript, sql, c#, ruby, R.

Databases Mysql, Postgressql, Oracle DB.

Others Microsoft BI tools, Sharepoint, Scrum Foundations, Laravel, Git, Unity, D3, Restful, Database Design.

Experience ____

Carvajal Tecnología y Servicios

Oct. 2016 - PRESENT

Applications engineer

- Implemented a purchasing BI model for Carvajal Educacion Colombia
- Implemented a SLA BI model for Carvajal Servicios
- Mantained and improved php applications
- · Worked with interdisciplinary teams over the course of several projects succesfully

Universidad del Valle Cali, Colombia

Software Engineer

Feb. 2016 - Jun. 2016

• Development of the web aplicattion Dicasa to support the data retrieval and analisyss of the existent capabilities regarding environmental health in the 32 departments and districts of colombia, tasked with supporting the proyect, designing and developing the solution for the data capture

Undergraduate Thesis project (Universidad del Valle, Prof. Victor Bucheli, Prof. Beatriz Florian)

Cali, Colombia

Student Aug. 2014 - May. 2015

· Implemented the prototype mobile application, VT-Mobile, which supports technological vigilance in the Universidad Del Valle. This prototype produces a set of visualizations and indicators from information extracted from a group of Scopus data. To create said visualizations and indicators the data goes through an enrichment process following the activities of: search, extraction, clustering, data analysis and data visualization. This tool makes possible to analyze the scientific production of the Escuela de Ingenieria de Sistemas y Computación.

March 17, 2018 Chris Santander · Curriculum Vitae